# Michael Joseph Rosenthal

rosenthalm93@gmail.com • Austin, TX in linkedin.com/in/michaeljosephrosenthal github.com/micimize stackoverflow.com/users/2234013/micimize

I have been a Software Engineer for more than 8 years, and have expertise with a variety of tools and frameworks at every level of the stack.

#### **PROFICIENCIES**

Skills: Machine Learning, Operations Engineering, Fullstack Architecture

Languages: Python, Dart, PL/pgSQL, Typescript, Javascript, shell scripting, GraphQL

Frameworks: fast.ai, pytorch, Flutter, Django, Flask, React

Interests: Machine Learning Self Study, Meditation, Travel, Philosophy, Writing

### **EXPERIENCE**

### Lead Data & Operations Engineer

Dec 2018 - Mar 2020

Environmental Defense Fund, Contract; Remote

Built the data infrastructure for the Air Quality Data Commons. Responsibilities included:

- A generalized air quality data pipeline, capable of ingesting a wide swath of air quality data formats
- A superset resource and <u>dashboard</u> generator for exposing and visualizing secure bigquery resources automatically.
- internal tools and APIs for accessing and managing data projects and schemas
- Google Cloud infrastructure management, deployments, and scripting
- Rigorous technical writing, including detailed documentation, roadmaps, architecture proposals, expositional issues, and user guides for a wide range of audiences.

### Fullstack Developer

Aug 2014 – Dec 2018

Various Contracts; Global (traveled)

As a contractor, I usually wear multiple hats, often managing AWS deployments, writing server and frontend logic, and integrating external services for the client as needed. Some specific solutions include:

- An interactive ETL pipeline builder written in Clojure
- Dockerized python microservices deployed to AWS
- A peerassets crypto wallet built with react-native

As well as a number of web applications built with Python and/or Javascript.

## Data Engineer/Analyst

Jun 2012 – May 2014

BuzzPoints; Austin, TX, USA

- Categorized millions of unlabeled records with PostgreSQL functions and modules
- Implemented PCI compliant ETL systems for sensitive, non-standardized client data
- Data reporting and visualization tools (Python, PostGIS)
- Implemented a raw text tokenization and labeling pipeline (Apache Camel, Elasticsearch)

#### **EDUCATION**

University of Texas at Austin Computer Science (Junior)

2011 - 2013